rallypoint.com 2015-03-16

# Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Introduction**

This privacy policy is designed to inform users of the RallyPoint website (the “Website”) about how we gather and use personal information collected by us in connection with use of the Website.  We will take reasonable steps to protect user privacy consistent with the guidelines set forth in this policy and with applicable U.S. laws.  In this policy, “user” or “you” means any person using the Website, whether by browsing the Website, creating a profile, submitting comments, blog entries or other content (“Content”), registering with us by creating a profile, or participating in any other activities available through the Website.  BY ACCESSING OR USING THE WEBSITE, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND, AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OUR WEBSITE TERMS AND CONDITIONS.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS, DO NOT USE THE WEBSITE.

**What Information Do We Collect?**

_Personal Information_ :  We collect the following personal information in connection with the Website:  (a) when you sign up to create a RallyPoint profile, we collect the personal information you disclose on the account registration form and your profile, including your email address, password, contact information, first name, last name, gender, birthday, branch of service, rank, military specialty, current unit and duty station, professional experience, educational background, and any other information you provide at registration or in your profile; (b) if you communicate with us by email, we will collect your email address; (c) when you visit the Website, our servers will automatically recognize your IP address; and (d) if you submit Content, you may, at your option, include information (such as your name or photograph) in the Content that can be used to identify you.  All of this information is referred to in this Policy as “Personal Information”.

_Web Tracking Information_ : We, and our third party service providers, may use web tracking technologies such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags and clear GIFs in order to operate the Website efficiently and to collect data related to usage of the Website and to web and email marketing conducted by us or on our behalf.  Such collected data (“Web Tracking Information”) may include the address of the websites you visited before and after you visited the Website, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, what pages in the Website you visit and what links you clicked on, and whether you opened email communications we send to you.  In order to collect Web Tracking Information and to make your use of the Website more efficient, we may store cookies on your computer.  In addition, the third party ad networks (“Ad Networks”) that we use to display advertising to you may also store their own cookies on your computer.  We may also use web tracking technologies that are placed in web pages on the Website or in email communications to collect information about actions that users take when they interact with the Website or such email communications, and Ad Networks and RallyPoint’s Contractors (as hereinafter defined) may also do so.  We do not correlate Web Tracking Information to individual user Personal Information.  Some Web Tracking Information may include data, such as IP address data and general segment information (e.g., your unit, career field, or information about your professional or educational background, that is unique to you.  You may be able to modify your browser settings to alter which web tracking technologies are permitted when you use the Website, but this may affect the performance of the Website.

**How Do We Use the Information We Collect?**

We collect information when you sync non-RallyPoint content – like your email address book or mobile device contacts – with your account. We use this information to improve your experience, help connect you with military or veterans organizations which we have vetted and which we believe to have the best interest of the member in mind, and allow you and your network to be better connected. You can remove your address book and any other synced information whenever you'd like.

You may use the RallyPoint contacts importer (or other similar mechanisms provided by RallyPoint) to upload individual contacts or your entire address book into RallyPoint. RallyPoint stores this information and uses it to help you manage and leverage your contacts. We also use this information to enhance your RallyPoint experience by helping you to grow your network by: identifying your contacts already on RallyPoint; informing your contacts that you are building your RallyPoint network; providing a template to send invitations to your contacts that have not registered with RallyPoint; and suggesting people you may know but who may not be in your RallyPoint contacts. RallyPoint may also use this information to show you and other members that you share the same uploaded contacts who may or may not be members. Please note that when you send an invitation to connect to another individual (a “connection”), that person may have access to your email address or, for SMS invitations, mobile number because it may be displayed in the invitation. RallyPoint may also remind you of pending invitations. Your RallyPoint connections may also have access to your email address.

RallyPoint may make other tools available to sync information with RallyPoint, and may also develop additional features that allow members to use their RallyPoint account in conjunction with other third-party services. For example, RallyPoint mobile applications may allow you to sync your device’s calendar, email and/or contacts apps with RallyPoint.

Another example are software tools that allow you to see RallyPoint and other public social media information about the people you email or meet with and leverage RallyPoint to help you gain insights from and grow your network. If you grant these products (mobile applications or other RallyPoint services that sync external email and calendar services permission to access your email and calendar accounts, they will access and may store some of your email header and calendar history information in order to match it to RallyPoint and other public social media profiles. RallyPoint’s products that sync with external email services may also temporarily cache message content for performance reasons, in a way that is unreadable by RallyPoint and its service providers.

Any information that you upload or sync with RallyPoint is covered by the User Agreement and this Privacy Policy. You can remove your information at your convenience using the features RallyPoint makes available. You can remove your address book and any other synced information at any time by requesting this.

_Personal Information_ :  We will use and store Personal Information for the purpose of delivering the Website to you, and to enhance and analyze the operation of the Website.  RallyPoint uses Personal Information to provide better, more customized services such as visibility into career opportunities, allowing professional opportunities to find you, or for serving more relevant advertisements on RallyPoint.  We may also use Personal Information for the internal operational and administrative purposes of the Website.

_Aggregate Information_ :  We will also use customer information to create aggregated data for analytical purposes.  This statistical information does not contain any Personal Information and is used to understand our customer base and to better serve our market.

_Web Tracking Information_ :  We use Web Tracking Information to administer the Website and to understand how well our Website is working, to store your user preferences and customize the Website pages you see, and to develop aggregate, statistical information on usage of the Websites.  This allows us to determine which features visitors like best to help us improve our Website, to personalize your user experience, and to measure overall effectiveness.

_Legal Exception_ :  Notwithstanding the above, we may in any event use Personal Information and other information collected through the Website to the extent required by law or legal process, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements (including this Privacy Policy and the _Terms of Service_ ) with you, or if in our reasonable discretion use is necessary to protect our legal rights or to protect third parties.

_Email Communications_ :  If you create an account and provide your email address, we will send you administrative and promotional emails.  If you wish to opt out of promotional emails, you may do so by following the “unsubscribe” instructions in the email, or by editing your account settings as described below.  All users receive administrative emails, and so you cannot opt out of them while you remain an account holder.

**What Information Do We Disclose to Third Parties?**

_Personal Information_ _:   _We will not disclose your Personal Information to any third parties except as follows:

(i) we may disclose information you have chosen to enter into your profile or elsewhere on the Website to potential employers and recruiters who are looking to hire personnel with your skill sets; or to companies,  or organizations looking to provide services based on your unique accomplishments or background.

(ii) to third party contractors engaged to provide services on our behalf (“Contractors”), such as performing marketing services, analyzing data and usage of the Website, operating the Website or providing support and maintenance services for the Website, or providing customer service.  We use reasonable efforts to enter into agreements with all Contractors that require Contractors to use the Personal Information they receive only to perform services for us.

(iii) when we have your consent to share the information.

_Web Tracking Information_ :  We disclose Web Tracking Information to third party advertisers, advertising agencies and Contractors, in order for us and such third parties to analyze the performance of the Website and the behavior of users, to operate and improve the Website, and to target advertising to users.  We may also publish this information in order to promote the Website.  In addition, Ad Networks may collect and use Web Tracking Information about your use of the Website and other websites to provide you with advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you; we do not control the manner in which Ad Networks use and disclose Web Tracking Information they collect.

_Aggregate Information_ :  We may disclose anonymous, aggregated information to third parties such as potential business partners, advertisers, and funding sources, in order to describe our business and operations.

_Network Operators_ : Use of the Website may involve use of the services of third party telecommunications carriers.  Such carriers are not our contractors, and any information that a carrier collects in connection with your use of the Website is not “Personal Information” and is not subject to this Privacy Policy.  We are not responsible for the acts or omissions of telecommunications carriers.

_Additional Disclosures_ :  We reserve the right to disclose any information we collect in connection with the Website, including Personal Information, (a) to any successor to our business as a result of any merger, acquisition, asset sale or similar transaction; and (b) to any law enforcement, judicial authority, or governmental or regulatory authority, to the extent required by law or if in our reasonable discretion disclosure is necessary to enforce or protect our legal rights or to protect third parties.

_RallyPoint Profile Privacy Settings_ :  You may choose which RallyPoint users can view your profile through your RallyPoint privacy settings.  You may choose to make your profile private so that it can only be seen by you.  If you set your profile as private, other RallyPoint users may not view your profile but your profile will be available to potential employers with access to RallyPoint.

_Other_ : RallyPoint is a dynamic, innovative environment, which means we are always seeking to improve the services we offer you. We often introduce new features, some of which may result in the collection of new information (for example, when the Endorsements feature launched, we began collecting information about skills for which members were endorsed and the individuals who endorsed them). Furthermore, new partnerships or corporate acquisitions may result in new features, and we may potentially collect new types of information.

**Notice of Privacy Rights to California Residents**

We disclose Personal Information to certain third party marketing firms, who may use your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes.  California law requires that you may request from us, not more than once per year, the following information: (a) a list of the categories of Personal Information that we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year; and (b) the names and addresses of all third parties that received Personal Information from us in the preceding calendar year for direct marketing purposes, and examples of the products or Websites marketed by such third parties, if known.  You may submit requests for such information to us by email to info@rallypoint.com.  If you do not want us to disclose your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes, you may notify us of that choice at any time.

**Privacy Settings/Opt Out**

If you would like to close your RallyPoint account or opt-out of email updates, please visit your [RallyPoint settings page](https://www.rallypoint.com/settings/edit) where you can control all your privacy settings or close your account. If you close your account, your data will no longer be displayed on the RallyPoint network and other RallyPoint members will not be able to find you.  Your removal will not remove records of past transactions or delete information stored in our data backups and archives.  Data on past transactions and data stored in backups and archives will be maintained and/or deleted in the ordinary course of RallyPoint’s business.

**Access and Updating of Information**

You may review or amend your profile, email address, or contact details at any time by using your settings panel in your account online.

**General**

_Security_ :  We use reasonable security precautions to protect the security and integrity of your Personal Information in accordance with this policy and applicable law.  However, no Internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that security breaches will not occur.  Without limitation of the foregoing, we are not responsible for the actions of hackers and other unauthorized third parties that breach our reasonable security procedures.

_Links_ : The RallyPoint website may contain links to other websites. RallyPoint is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. Users should be aware of this when they leave our website and review the privacy statements of each third party website. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Website.

_Amendments_ : RallyPoint may modify or amend this policy from time to time. If we make any material changes, as determined by RallyPoint, in the way in which Personal Information is collected, used or transferred, we will notify you of these changes by modification of this Privacy Policy, which will be available for review by you at the Website.  Notwithstanding any modifications we may make, any Personal Information collected by RallyPoint from you will be treated in accordance with the privacy policy in effect at the time information was collected, unless we obtain your consent otherwise.

_Children:_   RallyPoint does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from persons under 18 years of age, and no part of the Website is directed at persons under 18.  If you are under 18 years of age, then please do not use the Website. 

_Website Visitors from outside the United States_ :  RallyPoint and its servers are located in the United States and are subject to the applicable state and federal laws of the United States.  If you choose to access or use the Website, you consent to the use and disclosure of information in accordance with this privacy policy and subject to such laws.

_Effective Date of this policy_ : May 22nd, 2014

Military members and veterans value their privacy. Confirm your service on the next page for free, permanent access.

### We will never:

  * Contact any of your friends without your permission
  * Modify your profile in any way
